Waves are holding steady.
The drugs have made
her nerves super sensitive.
Still, no signs of inversion. Crank it up.
Nightmare's attacking!
Call for backup from Implement 2!
I finally found you,
Second Spirit... "Sister."
We're reading typical Spirit Wave levels.
The path connecting you
and the Spirits has normalized.
Really? That's a relief.
You had me worried
with your rampage the other day,
but I think it's safe
to resume regular checkups.
Sorry for all the trouble.
Though, I can't even
remember what happened.
Shido! Is your checkup done?
Hey, Tohka. Yeah, it went fine.
That's wonderful!
Thank goodness.
Yoshino's been worried sick! She was
holding Natsumi's hand the whole time!
I see. Sorry to trouble you, guys.
Don't be. It's not like we did anything.
Aren't your checkups next?
I'll buy stuff for dinner
on the way home, so...
Huh? Where's Kotori?
Oh, she's busy with
something in Exam Room 2.
Hurry and you might catch her.
All right. See you guys later.
--Okay!
--Yeah, yeah.
Exam Room 2...
It's this one, isn't it?
Calm your butt down and let me strip you!
K-Kotori?! Mana?!
--Big brother!
--Shido!
S-Sorry for intruding,
but it's wrong to force her into it!
You've totally got the wrong idea.
Kotori is forcing me to get a checkup!
Huh?
There's nothing wrong with me!
And why do I have to listen to you?
I told you! You need an exam with all
the body enhancements DEM's done to you!
My body's fine, thank you!
But you keep stopping me from going
on missions! I wanna help out, too!
Then let me exam you! I'll discover stuff
about your body you never knew!
Big brother! Save me!
"Happy New Year"
Nobody has a clue there's
a huge secret base under all this.
"Blast"
"Serial Publication"
Huh?
Whoa! What?!
A-Are you okay?!
Ar... ving.
Huh? Wh-What was that?
I'm... starving.
Huh?
Thanks, Boy.
Of course. Say, do you want me
to take you to the hospital?
Oh, heck no. It's not like I'm sick.
By the way, can you talk less polite?
It feels so stiff.
Oh... My apologies.
There you go again. But anyway...
I've been pushing 'em on you to show
my thanks, but you haven't reacted.
Are you a butt guy?
Wh-What are you talking about?!
Or a big boob lover that thinks
anything under 80cm doesn't count?
Sorry that my stack doesn't cut it.
Can you not put me in weird groups?
Oh. This building, please.
Huh?
Oof! Whew!
Thanks, Boy.
Are you a manga artist?
You know it. Was working so hard,
I forgot to eat.
I was heading to the store to buy food
when I found out how strong gravity is.
Huh?!
Is this what I think it is?!
Silver Bullet?!
I'm surprised you knew.
Are you a reader? Thanks!
Wait, hold up! That makes you
the author, Souji Honjo?!
Yup, that's right.
Y-You're not a guy?
It's my pen name.
My real one's Nia. Nia Honjo.
There's quite a few women using
guy pen names to write shonen manga.
You know, like Other Fake's Takajo.
Wha--?! Hiroki Takajo, too?!
Wait, it doesn't make sense!
I mean, I read Silver Bullet
in elementary school.
And the author stopped writing
for health reasons years ago.
It's been ten years since my debut...
I was out for a few reasons,
but I'm starting back up.
Check out the next volume. It'll be there.
Ten years ago?
But you don't even look 20 yet.
B-Boy!
Yeah, yeah. Lemme borrow your kitchen.
Delicious! Delicious! What is this
culinary magic?! What is it?!
What kind of life do you live?
All you have is beer in the fridge.
Man! I haven't had a hot meal
like this in a week!
I'll clean up and leave, so try not
to starve and collapse again.
Now, now! Not so fast, Boy!
You wanna earn some money?
What am I even doing?
Sorry. I don't usually use assistants,
but the deadline is tight this time.
It's fine, but what's the outfit for?
For reference, but also as
special thanks for your service!
Look! I've got no boobs,
but don't I got style?!
Here. Is this good enough?
Jeez! Trying to play cool?
Whoa, you're not bad!
More of where that came from!
Yeah, yeah.
All done!
I haven't focused that hard in ages!
Thanks for all the help!
Here! Come get your pay.
Wh-What are you doing?!
Don't be so fussy! C'mon, c'mon!
"Pay"
"Boy"
Is having small boobs a sin?!
Um... I'm leaving for real, so keep
the money. It was a learning experience.
Wait! Wait! That won't sit right with me!
How about this? Next Saturday,
I'll go on a date with you!
A date?
In Akihabara! I haven't bought
much lately, so I wanna go!
So I'm your bag carrier?
Erk!
Sorry, but ask someone else.
How about one of your friends?
Gee, I don't really have
any friends! But still...
Can you afford not to go?
Huh?
--There we go.
--Huh?
Isn't it your job to make Spirits
fall for you, Shido Itsuka?
It's been a month since Sister's escape...
I can punish the facility crew
if you'd like.
There's no need. Our talented
researchers are valuable. Besides...
Besides... What, Ike?
They couldn't have done a better job.
What gives?!
Give a better reaction than that!
--I just transformed for you!
--Huh?
I was expecting a
"Wh-What the heck?!" at least!
Or even better, "This girl's
transformation made my heart skip!"
Look, look! My Spirit Armor
is sexy, don'tcha think?
H-Hey! Quit teasing me!
Nia, I get that you're a Spirit,
but how do you know about me?
That I...
That you date Spirits
and make them fall for you?
Because... Raziel!
This is my Angel, Raziel.
It can see everything in the world.
In the world...?
What's happening anywhere in the world...
What anyone is doing...
For example,
how you just finished shopping
and were on the way home.
Huh? Then us meeting...?
You really thought it was a coincidence?
That some girl you found on the ground
turned out to be a Spirit?
A story that bad I don't want any part of.
So you purposely collapsed
knowing I'd help?
Yup.
And made me help with
your manga for a reason?
Just to meet the deadline.
You're kidding!
So, what are you after?
I'm not really after anything.
I just wanted to meet you.
Until recently, I was DEM's captive.
DEM? Westcott?!
Yup. Hence "away" for five years.
But I finally got a chance to escape,
and now I can get back to work!
Five years with DEM...
But while I was captive...
Ratatoskr, was it?
A secret organization
started looking for Spirits.
Um... So with your Raziel,
you know everything about me?
Not everything. Even Raziel
can't read the future or people's hearts.
But it can do this...
Huh?!
My body's moving on its own!
Eek!
Hold up! What was that all about?!
"Future Entry."
Everything written in Raziel is true--
Even if it's something added to it.
Future Entry?
Yup! The things written in
Raziel become true.
Having said that, it can be a pain
to write everything out.
I-I see. That does seem inconvenient.
Boy, you're not seeing
how terrifying Raziel can be.
Say, Boy... You seem to know
your way around a manga.
You've tried to
draw one before, haven't you?
I wonder what kind of manga it was?
Let's ask Mr. Raziel!
Let's see...
Ooh! The Black Knight, Lievan!
Uh, this girl needs some work.
"Flashing Thunder Wave!"
What a cool attack!
Flashing Thunder Wave!
All your original characters from
middle school! Talk about embarrassing!
S-Stop!
Well? See how terrifying Raziel can be?
Yes, it's incredible!
Sorry for doubting it.
Seeing how you helped with the manga
and your rice soup was tasty,
I thought I'd give you a chance.
A chance?
To make me fall for you with a date.
If you think you can win me over,
win me over.
I'm looking forward to next Saturday, Boy!
Akiba! I'm home!
Home...! Home...! Home...!
How to put this...
You're really decked out.
"Tokiya"
Shido, you copy?
Yeah, I hear you.
She doesn't seem hostile from
what you've said, but be on your guard.
Got it. Let's raise her happiness today
before DEM finds her.
Guys, sorry about the makeshift
command room,
but bear with it
until Fraxinus is repaired.
--Roger!
Now then, shall we begin our date?
"1. Cute clothes. They look good on you."
"2. What ugly clothes. I'll buy you something new."
"3. Oh? Those clothes will be fun to take off later."
Commander, we have choices!
Make your choice!
"1. Cute clothes. They look good on you."
"2. What ugly clothes. I'll buy you something new."
"3. Oh? Those clothes will be fun to take off later."
Oh? That's surprising.
The safest choice came in third.
"1. Cute clothes. They look good on you."
'Cuz, well... How to say it?
Nia's clothes are kinda..."
True. Complimenting that
get-up sounds like sarcasm.
Then, wouldn't two be best?
A harsh comment followed
by a glimpse of kindness!
Picking out her clothes is the way to go!
No, think about it.
Nia didn't come today to buy clothes.
Manga, light novels, figures, Blu-rays!
That's her goal!
Forcing her to shop for clothes
would be nothing short of torture!
Ooh! That's Nakatsugawa,
"The Man With 100 Wives," for you!
Your knowledge of love
transcends dimensions!
And according to Shido, she makes
naughty comments all the time.
Making a dirty joke might bring them closer.
Shido, try three.
What's up? Why so quiet, Boy?
Uh, no... Um, well...
O-Oh? Those clothes
will be fun to take off later.
Huh?
Uh, I...
You wanna take it all the way today?
I didn't think you were such a player!
Th-That's not what I--
You've gotta go that far to seal Spirit power?
Then lemme change my panties.
--Eh?!
--I'm kidding! I'm kidding!
You're getting advice from Ratatoskr, right?
Yay! Yay! Are you watching this, Kotori?!
I sure am. Very closely.
Thanks for carrying my stuff, Boy.
What a gentleman!
It's no big deal.
Yoink.
She's making all the moves, Shido!
I dunno what to say.
Ooh! Target spotted!
Let's go!
I haven't been here in so long,
it all feels so new!
Can't you keep up to date with Raziel?
I try to refrain from using Raziel
when it's not necessary--
'cuz I hate spoilers.
Did DEM make you use it
while you were captured?
Hmm? I don't really remember.
Huh? The whole five years?
They always kept tampering
with my mind and stuff.
But if they had such a hard time,
I doubt they were able to use it.
You never used Raziel
to see what happened to you?
Nah, I'd rather not.
I know it won't be pretty anyway.
"Chronicle
Kitan Tokiya"
Look at all the Tokiya goods!
You like him that much?
"Like" doesn't even begin to describe it!
He's the reason I got into manga!
Tokiya is my wife! A guy, but my wife!
"A Boy's Club for Two"
"Hands, Hearts, Together"
Uh, you like this stuff, too?
Hmph! Those without a
Maiden Circuit wouldn't understand.
Is that even a saying?
Pros in this field can perceive
anyone's nature in a single glance!
Timid bottom.
Hey! How did you classify me?!
The mood looks good. We haven't had
a date go this smooth in a while.
Yeah. It's about time for the next step.
Well, that was fun! I'm satisfied!
Yeah, I had a good time, too.
Let's swing by a café.
This way's a shortcut.
Nia!
Now's your chance, Shido!
N-Nia...
I...
Sorry.
It's no use.
Huh?
I don't wanna be chased by DEM,
so I really wouldn't mind if you sealed me...
But the truth is, I can only love 2D.
"Episode 01:
'Don't Panic. It's a Spirit's Trap.'"
Huh?
The opening narration can do
the episode preview. Now that's freedom.
Shido's dates are again underway!
Next time: "So Be It! 2D It Is!"
"Episode 02:
'So Be It! 2D It is!'"
Date A Live's fourth act has begun!